<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>0. Introduction on NGS analysis for gene regulation and epigenomics</title>
    <link>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 0. Introduction on NGS analysis for gene regulation and epigenomics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Presentation</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/01_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/01_presentation/</guid>
      <description>Dates 11-15 January 2021
General topic: Regulatory function of chromatin
Where This course will be held online in response to the coronavirus outbreak.
Overview This course will introduce biologists and bioinformaticians to the field of regulatory genomics.We will cover a broad range of software and analysis workflows that extend over the spectrum from the best practices in the quantitative analysis of ChIP-seq and ATAC-seq data to the analysis of the chromatin 3D structure (such as A/B compartments, chromatin loops or TADs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Program</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/02_program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/02_program/</guid>
      <description>Classes are from:
 2 to 8 pm Paris time. 1 to 7 pm London time. 8 am to 7 pm London time. 8 am to 2 pm NY time. 5 am to 11 am SF time.  Day 1 - Introduction to epigenomics, and 3D organisation of genomes. Lecture 1  Epigenomics introduction Hi-C protocol General processing of Hi-C data  Lab 1  Step-by-step processing of Hi-C data and integration with snakemake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Contacts</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/03_contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/03_contacts/</guid>
      <description>Contacts Jacques Serizay: jacques.serizay@pasteur.fr Cyril Matthey-Doret: cyril.matthey-doret@pasteur.fr Shared Google Doc:
AWS .pem file: file </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Rstudio and Jupyter Notebooks</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/04_rstudio-and-jupyternotebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/04_rstudio-and-jupyternotebooks/</guid>
      <description>Rstudio and Jupyter Notebooks offer graphical interfaces to facilitate the interaction between a user and an underlying programming language (this is sometimes called IDE, or integrated development environment). They can be very useful when a user is not necessarily proficent with command line-based computing. However, such graphical interfaces are not always able to connect to services such as AWS.
Since most of the preliminary analysis we do is on AWS, we&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to use Jupyter Notebooks directly on AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Prerequisites and required local config</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/05_prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/NGS-analysis_Physalia_2021/introduction/05_prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Unix command line: familiarity with command-line tools is expected. If a refresher is needed (hopefully not), please go over this tutorial and its companion cheatsheet . R/Bioconductor: Chapters 4 to 8 of the comprehensive book from Kasper D. Hansen available under the CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 license [PDF]  Python Snakemake Jupyter  Local configuration  Configured SSH client (already installed on Linux/Mac machines) FileZilla IGV  AWS configuration Install and set up Conda # Install Conda wget https://repo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
